Dan Oliver

Phone (541) 951-5783 | Email: idanoliver@gmail.com | Bend, Oregon

OBJECTIVE:

To bring my small business management experience to BendTECH's Community and Operations Management role. Having founded, owned and operated a small service business for 5+ years, I believe I could bring valuable skills and experience in day-to-day management as well as systematic improvements to the user experience across the service lifecycle and to the community as a whole.

RELEVANT SKILLS & EXPERIENCE:

- <u>Small Business Management</u> Built a small business from nothing to a profitable Quarter Million dollar a year business
- Excellent written and verbal communicator with very high Emotional Intelligence.
- Relentlessly work to improve <u>customer experience</u> across touchpoints and mediums
- <u>Sales</u> both business-to-business and business-to-consumer (~70% close ratio)
- Use Xero to manage company financials, including accounts receivable, invoicing, and record-keeping (formerly used Quickbooks)
- Built and manage company website using Wordpress (www.oliverarborcare.com). Also know some HTML and CSS
- <u>Track website statistics</u> via Google Analytics; Track customer satisfaction through followups and Net Promoter Score surveys
- Manage marketing activities including customer experience improvements to drive Client Lifetime Value/word-of-mouth referrals, SEO, Google AdWords, customer pipeline management, and branding
- Bring an empathetic approach to customer service. Communicate clearly, early and often to avoid client/employee misunderstandings
- Creative and tenacious problem-solver/solution-seeker
- Comfortable with and <u>quick to learn SaaS and many software platforms</u>: Sketch, Photoshop, Zapier, Slack, Asana, Microsoft/Apple/Google Office suites, etc.
- Very <u>detail oriented</u> manage high expectations and juggle multiple priorities and timelines.
- Always growing Currently learning everything I can about Customer-Centered Experience Design (CX, UX, Service Design, etc) through books and online classes. Working toward Certified Customer Experience Professional through Customer Experience Professionals Association (CXPA).

WORK HISTORY:

2012 -Present Oliver Arbor Care, Inc.

Bend, OR

Owner/President, Customer Experience Design, Customer Service, Sales

2010 - 2012 Ward Tree Care Portland, OR Crew Foreman, Lead Climber, Sales, Customer-facing

2004 - 2010 Bartlett Tree Service Medford, OR Climber, Sales, Customer-facing

EDUCATION:

Current Eastern Oregon University - Business - Marketing Online

Working toward Bachelor of Science degree in Business Administration

with a Marketing concentration. Part-time/online.

Cornell University - Customer-Centered Product and Service Design

Certificate course - Online

2017 - 2017 HubSpot Academy - Inbound Marketing Certification

Online class/certification in Inbound Marketing

2016-2016 Community Tree Management Institute - Alumni PNW

Course series held in various locations in Oregon and Washington training

Online

participants in management strategies for community trees.

2011 - 2012 Portland Community College Portland, OR

2010 - 2011 Central Oregon Community College Bend, OR

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE:

- Served on planning committee for Pacific Northwest region's annual arboriculture conference - taking ownership of coordinating the climbing competition: arranging for use of Drake park, soliciting and organizing volunteers, setting up catering, etc.
- Freelance Copywriting
- Project work Crime & Partners Marketing Agency creating/researching ad campaign pitch
 material Fall 2017
- Photography internship The Bulletin newspaper in Bend Spring 2010
- Photo Editor/ Photographer The Broadside (COCC newspaper) 2010
- Volunteer Crew Leader Friends of Trees in Portland, OR 2012
- Volunteer event photographer Roll35 in Bend Winter 2010